考虑一下我们正在查看此对象。它被白光源照亮
Consider that we are viewing this object. It is being illuminated by a white light source
并且相机返回这些RGB值或三刺激值。想象一下，现在
and the camera is returning these RGB values or tristimulus values. Imagine now that the
白光源的强度正在降低。我们观察到的是外观
intensity of the white light source is being reduced. What we observe is that the appearance
对象的变化但很明显，对象本身的颜色不能改变，因为
of the object changes but clearly the color of the object itself cannot change because
颜色是物体的物质属性-苹果即使在黑暗中仍然是红色的
the color is a material property of the object — an apple is still red, even if it is in a dark
房间-而我们观察到的是，随着照明水平降低了三刺激
room — and what we observe is that as the lighting level has been reduced the tristimulus
价值观发生了变化它们都变小了，但三刺激之间的比例
values have changed; they have all become smaller, but the ratio between the tristimulus
值保持不变，我们想要做的是找到一些转换方法
values remains the same and what we would like to do is to find some way to transform
三个三刺激值到一个亮度值，也许两个颜色值。
the three tristimulus values to one brightness value and perhaps two color values.
一种方法是将RGB值转换为色度坐标和我们
One way to do this is to transform the RGB values into chromaticity coordinates and we
将RGB值除以总和，通过总三刺激，我们最终得到这些变量，
divide the RGB values by the sum, by the total tristimulus, we end up with these variables,
小R，小G和小B.并且很容易证明这些在零之间变化
little R, little G and little B. And it is easy to show that these vary between zero
一个。它也很容易证明它们总和为一。因此，其中一个坐标
and one. It is also easy to show that they sum to one. Therefore, one of the coordinates
是多余的，通常我们只考虑小R和小G值。
is redundant and typically we consider just the little R and little G values.
考虑这个有效的例子，类似于我们之前看过的事情：白光下降
Consider this worked example, similar to things we have looked at before: white light falling
在红苹果上产生这种三刺激值。现在考虑有一个云
on to a red apple and producing this tristimulus value. Now consider that there is a cloud
在光源前面，整体照度水平已经降低了
in front of the light source, the overall illumination level has been reduced and the
三刺激值现在具有不同的值，比我们之前的三刺激值更小。
tristimulus value now has a different value, smaller tristimulus value then we had before.
让我们考虑一个有效的例子：在第一种情况下，我们可以计算色度
Let’s consider a worked example: in the first case we can compute the chromaticity
小R和小G的坐标。对于有云的第二种情况
coordinates of little R and little G. For the second case where there was a cloud in
在光源前面，降低整体照度，我们可以计算色度坐标
front of the light source, lower overall illumination, we can compute the chromaticity coordinates
我们可以看到它们是相同的，我们能够做的就是要考虑因素
and we can see that they are the same and what we have been able to do then is to factor
消除强度的影响，只保留两个数字，提供一些表示
out the effect of intensity and retain just two numbers which provide some representation
的颜色。我们考虑一个二维坐标
of color. Let’s consider a two dimensional coordinate
轴小R和小G的系统。这个点R等于1，G等于
system with the axis little R and little G. This point where R equals one and G equals
没有对应纯红色。其中R等于零，G等于一等于纯
nought corresponds to pure red. Where R equals nought and G equals one corresponds to pure
绿色和此点在R和G都等于零的原点对应
green and this point at the origin where R and G are both equal to zero corresponds to
纯蓝色。色度坐标是不可能的
pure blue. It is not possible for a chromaticity coordinate
存在于蓝线上方的空间中，这来自于很少的约束
to exist in the space above the blue line and this comes from the constraint that little
R，加上小G，加上小B必须等于1。
R, plus little G, plus little B has to equal one.
在之前的一个讲座中，我们讨论了伽玛编码的概念，这就是有一个
In an earlier lecture we discussed the concept of gamma encoding this is where there is a
进入相机的光的亮度与幅度之间的非线性变换
non-linear transformation between the brightness of the light entering the camera and the magnitude
离开相机的信号今天几乎所有相机都有伽玛编码
of the signal leaving the camera. Almost all cameras today have gamma encoding in them
伽玛值通常约为2.2。伽玛编码对色度有何影响
and the gamma value is typically around 2.2. What effect does gamma encoding have on chromaticity
坐标？我们将用另一个有用的例子说明这一点。
coordinates? We will illustrate this with another worked example.
我们将使用前面示例中的三刺激或RGB值与完整的太阳
We will use the tristimulus or RGB values from the earlier example with the full sun
和阴云密布的太阳照射，第一步是计算伽玛编码的RGB值，
and the clouded sun illumination and the first step is to compute the gamma encoded RGB values,
它们在这里显示，我们可以使用MATLAB非常方便地完成这项工作。
and they are shown here, and we can do this very easily and conveniently using MATLAB.
现在让我们计算色度坐标，在第一种情况下，它是用于完全照明
Now let’s compute the chromaticity coordinates and in the first case it is for the full illumination
条件，这里是R和G值。对于低照度的第二种情况，
condition and here are the R and G values. For the second case with lower illumination,
我们计算色度坐标，我们看到它们与第一个相同
we compute the chromaticity coordinates and we see they are the same as for the first
案件。所以我们再一次考虑了照明的影响，我们留下了
case. So once again we have factored out the effect of illumination and we are left with
两个代表颜色的数字。对于这种使用伽玛编码的情况，我们已经考虑了因素
two numbers which represent the color. For this case with gamma encoding, we have factored
效果照明，这是一件好事。但实际的色度坐标
out the effect illumination and that is a good thing. But the actual chromaticity coordinates
与我们之前在没有伽玛编码的情况下计算的情况具有不同的值。
have a different value to the case we computed earlier without gamma encoding.